

ALEXANDER TRESPALACIOS

Telecommunications Engineering

Copacabana - Colombia

jrios714@soyudemedellin.edu.co

+573108202461

https://ijrios.github.io/



https://github.com/ijrios

ABOUT ME

Ethnically ambiguous and Catholic, passionate about telecommunications and programming. My academic training and experience are enriched with solid skills in various areas such as Machine learning, supervised learning, cluster analysis, .NET developer, Python developer, among other languages. My knowledge ranges from programming languages such as C# (most used), Python and Java, MATLAB and C++, to web software development tools with ASP.NET MVC and Node js with frameworks such as Flask and FastAPI, JSF, JSP, Servlets, PrimeFaces and React Js (capable of developing responsive web pages). All this is complemented by knowledge of AWS, Kubernetes, Dockers, automation and control systems (PLC) and optical and wireless network planning. Thus reflecting my versatility and adaptability to address technical challenges.

PROJECTS

- CardioVigilant Al: Solution to the challenge chosen for the data science hackathon. – Flask Pyhton, Machine Learning
- Systema IoT Retrofit Aquae Intelligentes Tank -Python
- Bookstore (Reviews Reservations) OOP Java
- Bancolombia Operational Excellence website .Net
 MVC
- IoT Retrofit home automation control system for sliding windows.

LANGUAGES

Spanish
English
Latín

SKILLS

.NET
C#

React JS

Python

SQL

Mach. Learn.

Java

EDUCATION

2016 - 2024 Medellín, Colombia

Engineer's degree, Telecommunications EngineeringUniversity of Medellín

2004 - 2015 Cáceres, Antioquia

Basic and High School

Institución educativa Monseñor Gerardo Patiño

EXPERIENCES

Enero. 2024 - Present

Medellín, Colombia

BANCOLOMBIA

Engineer Intern

- .Net Developer ASP.NET MVC and Layered architecture
- C#, SQL, Javascript.
- Bank process automation, developer.
- Automate the monitoring and loading of Bancolombia's installed capacity and and other projects

July. 2023 - Dec 2023

Medellín, Colombia

UNIVERSITY OF MEDELLIN

Academic Monitor

- Development of machine learning processes in Python
- Digital holographic images applying image processing
- · Phase object recovery using digital holographic
- Convolutional neural network architecture with Python

WINNERS

HACKATHON DATA SCIENCE - FIRST PLACE:

«CardioVigilant_AI»

Institución Universitaria Pascual Bravo Y Ruta N

REFERENCES

Jeeny Cuantindioy Full-time Professor Phone: 3002503586

E-mail: Jenny.cuantindioy@udea.edu.co

Jakeline Ramos Session Boss Phone: 3016603239 E-mail: jaramos@bancolombia.com.co Mario Alberto Luna Full-time Professor Phone: 3002072673 E-mail: mluna@udem.com.co

Felix Aviléz Lawyer Phone: 3012944917

E-mail: felixavilez17@gmail.com